Lurelle Guild Papers
Lurelle Guild Papers
- Shop drawings
  - Mohawk Carpet Mills, 1946 - 1950 (Box 51)
  - Montgomery Ward, 5 folders (Box 51)
  - Murray (Auditorium), 1950 (Box 52)
  - Murray Corporation, 1950; 2 folders (Box 52)
  - National Enameling and Stamping Company, 1 folder
    - 1936, 2 folders (Box 52)
  - National Gypsum Company (Box 52)
  - National Radiator Company, 2 folders
    - 1936 (Box 52)
  - National - U.S. Radiator, 1956 (Box 52)
  - Nedicks Specs and Data (Box 52)
  - New Haven Clock Company
    - 1946 (Box 52)
    - 1946 - 1950 (Box 52)
  - New Haven Railroad, 6 folders (Box 52)
  - New Haven Railroad
    - and New York, 3 folders (Box 53)
    - Display, 1947 - 1948 (Box 53)
    - Exhibit, 1947 (Box 53)
  - New York Central, 1954 - 1955 (Box 53)
  - New York Dress Institute (Box 53)
  - New York, New Haven, and Hartford Railroad (Box 53)
  - Norge Corporation (Box 53)
  - Nutri Cola, 1947; 2 folders (Box 53)
  - Owens - Illnois (Box 53)
  - Ox-Fibre Brush Company, 1 folder
    - 1946 - 1050 (Box 53)
    - Rejects (Box 53)
  - Para Manufacturing Company (Box 53)
  - Martin Parry - Ming Sung, 1948 (Box 53)
  - Pitney Bowes, 3 folders
    - 1949 - 1950 (Box 53)
  - Pitney Bowes (oversize) (Oversize 12)
  - Pittsburgh Plate Glass Company (Box 54)
  - Pond's Extract Company (Box 54)
  - Porch and Fence (Dr. White) (Box 54)
  - Porter Kleinert, Sarafal, Pittsburgh Plate Glass, etc. (Box 54)
  - Pressed Steel Car Company, 1946 - 1950; 4 folders (Box 54)
  - Pullman Car and Manufacturing Corporation, 2 folders (Box 54)
  - Radiant Heater Corporation, 1945; 2 folders (Box 54)
  - Railraods (Box 54)
  - Remington, 2 folders
    - 1946 (Box 54)
    - 1946 - 1950 (Box 54)
  - Rensie Watch Company, 1945 (Box 54)
  - Revlon, 2 folders (Box 54)
  - Richardson - Boynton Company (Box 54)
  - Risdon Manufacturing Company, 1946 - 1950 (Box 54)
  - Roaster, 2 folders (Box 54)
  - Salz Brothers (Box 54)
  - Salisbury Furniture Company (Box 54)
  - Savafal (Box 54)
  - Schick (Box 54)
  - Scranton Lace Company
    - 1946 (Box 54)
    - 1948, 2 folders (Box 54)
  - Seaboard Airline Railway
    - 1945 (Box 55)
    - 1946 (Box 55)
  - Seeburg
    - 1945 (Box 55)
    - 1946 (Box 55)
  - Servel, 2 folders
    - Buildings and Displays (Box 55)
    - Plywood Models (Box 55)
    - Unfinished Tracings (Box 55)
    - 1946 (Box 55)
    - Trailer, 1946 - 1950 (Box 55)
  - Sheer Company, H.M. (Box 55)
  - Sherlin (Box 55)
  - Singer (Box 55)
  - Solo Products, 1947; 2 folders (Box 55)
  - A.G. Spaulding Brothers, 1946 (Box 55)
  - A.G. Spaulding Brothers, 1948 (Box 55)
  - Speakman (Box 55)
  - Standard Gas Equipment (Box 55)
  - Stanley Electric Tools (Box 55)
  - Mr. Stanley's Dining Room, 1946 - 1950 (Box 55)
  - J.P. Stevens's
    - 1945 (Box 55)
    - 1946 (Box 55)
    - 1948, Working drawings (Box 55)
    - 1948 - 1949 (Box 55)
    - 1950 (Box 55)
  - Sunspray Bottle (Box 55)
  - Sylvania Electric Products, 1 folder
    - 1946 (Box 55)
    - 1947 (Box 55)
    - 1948, Lighting center (Box 55)
    - 1950, Offices (Box 55)
    - 1946 - 1950 (Box 55)
  - Textron, 1946 - 1950 (Box 56)
  - Underwood Elliott Fisher Company, 4 folders
    - 1946 (Box 56)
  - Union News
    - Broadway Restaurant (Box 56)
    - 1948, Working Drawings (Box 56)
    - 1947 - 1948 (Box 56)
    - 1949, Miscellaneous (Box 56)
  - William Van Buran (Box 56)
  - Van Buran Prints, 1949 (Box 56)
  - Vases (Box 56)
  - Vermont Marble (Box 56)
  - Virginia - Lincoln Furniture Corporation (Box 56)
  - Vita - Brush
    - 1948 (Box 56)
  - Vortex Dixie Cups, 1946 - 1950 (Box 56)
  - Walker and Pratt (Box 56)
  - Wallace - Jewelry, 1946 (Box 56)
  - Wearever Aluminum Company, 1 folder
    - 1946 (Box 56)
    - 1950 (Box 56)
  - Wearever Pen and Pencil Company (Box 56)
  - Westinghous, 4 folders (Box 56)
  - Westinghouse, 2 folders
    - Dramaturgy Layouts (Box 57)
    - Laundramat (Box 57)
    - Range, 4 folders (Box 57)
    - 1946, Texas Show (Box 57)
    - 1946 (Box 57)
    - 1947, Experimental Housing Project (Box 57)
    - 1947, Kitchen Planning; 2 folders (Box 57)
    - 1948 (Box 58)
    - 1946 - 1950, Experimental House (Box 58)
    - 1946 - 1950, House of Frisby (Box 58)
    - 1946 - 1950 (Box 58)
    - 1951 (Box 58)
  - Weston Electrical Instrument Company, 2 folders (Box 58)
  - Taylor Wharton (Box 58)
  - W.H. Wheeler (Box 58)
  - White Company, N.C., 2 folders (Box 58)
  - Dr. White's Cottage, 1949 (Box 58)
  - Whitney Chain and Cable (Box 58)
  - Whitney Chain Company, 1950 (Box 58)
  - Wilson Welder, 2 folders (Box 58)
  - Winchester Repeating (Box 58)
  - Wood Office Furniture Institute, 2 folders (Box 58)
  - Wooster Rubber Company (Box 58)
  - World's Fair (Box 58)
  - Yessler - House for Thad. Rhindoller, 1946 (Box 58)
  - Miscellaneous (Oversize 4)
  - Miscellaneous (Oversize 5)
  - Miscellaneous (Oversize 6)
  - Miscellaneous (Oversize 7)
  - Miscellaneous (Oversize 8)
  - Miscellaneous (Oversize 9)
  - Miscellaneous (Oversize 10)
  - Miscellaneous (Oversize 11)
- Design work
  - Advertising
    - Armstrong Tile (Oversize 14)
    - C.F. Church Manufacturing Company (Box 58)
    - Columbia Mills (Oversize 14)
    - General (Box 58)
    - General Time (Oversize 15)
    - Hendryx (Box 58)
    - Hendryx Bird Cages (Oversize 15)
    - Kayser (Oversize 15)
    - Pressed Steel Car Company, Inc. (Box 58)
    - Sylvania (Oversize 15)
    - Vinatile (Oversize 14)
    - Westinghouse (Oversize 14)
    - Lurelle Guild's drawings (Oversize 13)
  - Alcoa Steamship Passenger Vessel Notebook (Box 58)
  - Alcoa Steamship
    - 57 Bulkhead colors, 1 folder (Box 59)
    - Samples, swatches (Box 59)
    - Samples, swatches (Box 60)
  - Chase Lighting Fixtures, 3 vols. (Box 60)
  - Chase Lighting Lamps, 2 vols. (Box 60)
  - Christian Dior (Box 60)
  - Drawings, 3 folders (Box 60)
  - Drawings, paintings, and displays (oversize)
    - Alcoa Steamship, Misc. (Oversize 16)
    - Kings Lotion, Electrolux, Misc. (Oversize 17)
    - Misc. (Oversize 18)
    - Misc. (Oversize 19)
    - Misc. (Oversize 20)
    - Misc. (Oversize 21)
    - Pitney Bowes, Misc. (Oversize 22)
    - Stanley Tools, Underwood, Bermuda Colonial Trademark, Misc. (Oversize 23)
    - Westinghouse, Misc. (Oversize 24)
  - General (oversize)
    - Insulation, material, misc. (Oversize 25)
    - Misc. (Oversize 26)
    - Misc., whitings, source material, other artists (Oversize 27)
    - Mohawk Carpet, Armstrong Linoleum, Kroehler Furniture (Oversize 28)
    - New Haven Railroad, Molding, Misc., Mrs. G's Book, Catalin Bath Brush, Alcoa Steamship (Oversize 29)
    - Pitney Bowes (Oversize 30)
    - Seagrams, misc, source material, by other artists (Oversize 31)
    - Shower curtain (Oversize 32)
  - Johns - Manville, 3 folders (Box 60)
  - Miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 60)
  - Mohawk Rug (Box 60)
  - New Haven Railroad, 1 folder
    - 1947 - 1950 (Box 60)
  - Nutri Cola, 1947 - 1950 (Box 60)
  - Pitney Bowes, 2 folders (Box 60)
  - Pitney Bowes, 2 folders
    - 70 lb. Scale (Box 61)
  - Prints (Box 61)
  - Assorted samples (Box 62, 63)
  - Material samples
    - Billhardt's House (Box 64)
  - Seaboard Railroad, 1947 - 1950 (Box 64)
  - Solo, 1947 - 1950 (Box 64)
  - Source material - by other artists, 7 folders, 1 vol. (Box 64)
  - Spaulding (Box 64, 65)
  - Sylvania (Box 65)
  - Whitings (Box 65)
- Photographs
  - Alcoa Aluminum Company of America, 2 folders
    - Logos and products (Oversize 34)
    - Scrapbook of logos (Oversize 33)
    - Table ornaments (Box 65)
    - 1951 (Box 65)
  - Alcoa Steamship, 2 folders
    - Lamps, 1946 (Box 65)
    - 1948 (Box 65)
  - Aluminum Cooking Utensil, 2 folders (Box 65)
  - Aluminum Museum, 1 vol. (Box 65)
  - American Automotive Maintenance Machinery Company, 1945 (Box 65)
  - American District Telegraph, 2 folders (Box 65)
  - American Druggist, publication
    - 1945 (Box 65)
  - American Locomotive, 2 folders (Box 65)
  - American - South African Line, 1948 (Box 65)
  - Antiques (Box 65)
  - Aquatic, G.A. Stove (Box 65)
  - Armstrong Linoleum Company (Box 65)
  - Bourjois, 1947 - 1948 (Box 65)
  - C.B. and Q. Railroad (Box 65)
  - Philip Carey, 1948 (Box 65)
  - Carrier Corporation (Box 65)
  - Chase Brass and Copper (Box 65)
  - Church, C.F. (Box 65)
  - Columbia Mills (Box 65)
  - Crystal Room, 1949 (Box 65)
  - Dixie Cup Company, 2 folders (Box 65)
  - Edwards and Company, 2 folders (Box 65)
  - Elastic Stop Nut Corporation, 2 folders (Box 65)
  - Electric Railway (Box 65)
  - Electric Railway President's Corporation (Box 65)
  - Electrolux (Box 66)
  - Everready Flashlight (Box 66)
  - Federal Housing Administration (Box 66)
  - Fram Corporation (Box 66)
  - Fuller, Smith and Ross (Box 66)
  - Furniture (Box 66)
  - General Stoker (Box 66)
  - Goblin Electric Cleaner Company, Ltd. (Box 66)
  - Gold Medal (Box 66)
  - Guild, personal (Box 66)
  - Guild Round Refrigerator (Box 66)
  - Gulf Oil Corporation, 2 folders (Box 66)
  - A.B. Hendryx Company, 2 folders (Box 66)
  - Holcomb and Hoke (Box 66)
  - House of Frisby (Box 66)
  - Howe Scale Company (Box 66)
  - Industrial Food Crafts, Inc., 1946 (Box 66)
  - International Silver (Box 66)
  - The Jewett Refrigerator Co. Inc. (Box 66)
  - Johns - Manville (Box 66)
  - Johns - Manville, 3 folders (Box 66)
  - Julius Kahn Inc. (Box 66)
  - Julius Kayser, 1 folder
    - 1946 (Box 66)
    - 1947 (Box 66)
    - 1948, Chicago Showroom (Box 66)
    - 1948 (Box 66)
  - Kensington, Inc., 1 folder
    - Displays (Box 66)
  - Kittinger (Box 66)
  - M (Box 66)
  - Maryland Distillery (Box 66)
  - Miscellaneous, 6 folders (Box 66)
  - Miscellaneous, 2 folders
    - 1946 (Box 67)
  - Miscellaneous (oversize) (Oversize 35)
  - Miscellaneous (oversize) (Oversize 36)
  - Miscellaneous (oversize) (Oversize 37)
  - Miscellaneous (oversize), Lurelle Guild's designs (Oversize 38)
  - Mohawk Carpet (Box 67)
  - Montogomery Ward (Box 67)
  - Murray Corporation of America, 2 folders (Box 67)
  - National Radiator Company (Box 67)
  - Negatives, 2 boxes (Box 67)
  - New Haven Railroad, 2 folders
    - Stations (Box 67)
    - 1947 (Box 67)
  - New York Dress Institute (Box 67)
  - Norge Corporation, 2 folders (Box 67)
  - Nutri - Cola International Corporation, 2 folders (Box 67)
  - Ox-Fibre Brush Company (Box 68)
  - Philadelphia Art Alliance (Box 68)
  - Pictures (Box 68)
  - Pitney Bowes, 1948 (Box 68)
  - Walker Pratt (Box 68)
  - Pressed Steel Car Company, 2 folders (Box 68)
  - Products and Packaging (Box 68)
  - Pullman (Box 68)
  - Pullmatch, 2 folders (Box 68)
  - Savafal (Box 68)
  - Scranton Lace, 1948 (Box 68)
  - Servel Incorporated, 1 folder
    - Air Conditioning (Box 68)
  - Silver - Brass - Ware (Box 68)
  - Slides - 1 Box (Box 68)
  - Solo (Box 68)
  - Spaulding, A.G. (Box 68)
  - J.P. Stevens Company (Box 68)
  - Sylvania Electric Company
    - 1945 (Box 68)
    - 1950, Offices (Box 68)
    - Sylvania Lighting Center, 1948 (Box 68)
    - Sylvania Lighting Center, 1949 (Box 68)
    - Timkin Axles (Box 68)
  - Transportation Future Ideas (Box 69)
  - Underwood Elliot Fisher (Box 69)
  - Union News, 1948 (Box 69)
  - Ingersoll Waterbury Company (Box 69)
  - Westinghouse
    - Waldorf Display (Box 69)
    - Texas Show, 1946; 2 folders (Box 69)
  - Weston Electrical Instrument (Box 69)
- Printed material
  - Books
    - 1 vol. (Box 69)
    - 2 vols. (Box 70)
    - In Collaboration with Lurelle Guild, 1 vol. (Box 70)
  - Magazines
    - Miscellaneous, 4 folders (Box 70)
    - Modern Home, 2 folders (Box 70)
  - Magazines (oversize) (Oversize 39)
  - Magazine clipping, advertising, etc., 2 folders (Box 70)
  - Magazine clippings, advertising, etc. (Box 71)
  - Newspapers (Box 71)
  - Pamphlets, 3 folders (Box 71)
  - Pamphlets, articles, catalogs, 9 folders (Box 71, 72)
  - Pamphlets, articles, catalogs, newsclippings, advertisng, pictures (oversize) (Oversize 40)
- Memorabilia
  - Appointment books
    - Miscellaneous notes (Box 72)
    - undated, 4 vols. (Box 72)
    - 1937 - 1940, 2 vols. (Box 72)
    - 1941 - 1948, 24 vols. (Box 72)
    - 1948 - 1949, 6 vols. (Box 73)
    - 1950 - 1952, 20 vols. (Box 73)
    - 1953 - 1955, 26 vols. (Box 74)
    - 1955 - 1958, 26 vols. (Box 75)
    - 1958 - 1959, 12 vols. (Box 76)
    - 1960 - 1962, 15 vols. (Box 76)
    - 1962 - 1967, 19 vols. (Box 77)
  - Bills, gasoline and automobile, 1964 - 1968 (Box 77)
  - Books
    See also Miscellaneous (oversize)
    - Croker's Dictionary of Arts (Box 78)
    - Grammar of Ornament (Box 78)
  - Correspondence
    - Miscellaneous (Box 78)
  - Etching block (Box 78)
  - 1 large key (Box 78)
  - Magic designer (Box 78)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 78)
  - Personal possessions (Box 78)
  - Work Dome for clients, 1 File Box (Box 78)
  - Miscellaneous (oversize), 2 scrapbooks, 1 photograph, 2 books, newspapers (Oversize 41)
- Models
  - Bowls, candle holders (Box 79)
  - Coffee pots, pitchers, misc. (Box 80)
  - Electric appliances, misc. (Box 81)
  - Electric appliance, molds (Box 82)
  - Electric appliances, pitchers, miscellaneous (Box 83)
  - Flat painted glass (Oversize 43, 44)
  - Glass bowl, dishes (Box 84)
  - Glass serving bowl and matching glasses, etc. (Box 85)
  - Glass serving dishes (Box 86)
  - Glass serving dish (oversize) (Oversize 45)
  - Green cushion chair (Oversize 53)
  - Metal chair, silver (Oversize 52)
  - Metal container, assembled metal strip (Oversize 51)
  - Metal containers (Oversize 50)
  - Molds (Box 87)
  - Molds, serving dishes (Box 88)
  - Molds, wooden models, for aluminum industrial use (Oversize 46)
  - Pans, pitchers, coffee pots (Box 89)
  - Plastic trays (Oversize 47)
  - Railroad car (Oversize 49)
  - Serving dishes, bowls (Box 90)
  - Serving dishes, bowls, parts of dishes (Box 91)
  - Serving dishes, trays (Box 92)
  - Miscellaneous, aluminum samples, electric appliance parts, plastic bowl, misc. (Oversize 42)
  - Miscellaneous, vacuum, electric light, suede strips, misc. (Oversize 48)